Okay, so in this video then, there's two
other contract terms I want to just
briefly talk about just in case they come
up on the P&P exam.
And that are these two types
of contracts are these two
terms called a completion
contract and a term contract.
All right, so let's talk
about the difference
then between the completion
and the term contract.
Now completion contract, most of the
contracts that most of us are used to,
right, is a completion contract.
That's what we generally think of.
When we think of a
contract, that's usually
what we think of, a completion contract.
But basically, the buyer is going to
receive a good or service from the seller.
The seller has been
hired to perform a good
or service or deliver a good or service.
And when they deliver
that good or service,
they get paid or they
get the final payment.
That is generally what we think of when we
think of a contract.
So when you're building a house,
then the final delivery is the house.
Once a house is complete, then they
deliver that house to you.
The builder delivers the house to you and
the contract is complete.
You pay them the final payment when you
are installing a computer system.
Again, you've hired an external vendor to
install, do the implementation and once
they've delivered, and
once they've complete,
that's when you pay the final payment.
Sure, there's going to be some
payments in between, but the
final payment is upon delivery,
delivery of the good or service.
So that is a completion contract.
Now, the term contract, on the other hand,
there's no real delivery at the end of it.
It just refers to the scope, as it says
here, in general terms, very high level.
And really, the best thing, to think of it
is it's a level of effort.
It's more of a level of effort.
So there's no real delivery at the end,
right?
We don't know what the outcome is
necessarily.
There might not be an
outcome, but we've just hired
this organization to deliver
this level of effort work.
So, for example, research and development
projects.
It's a research and development project.
We don't know what the outcome is going to
be.
So we've hired this vendor to perform 500
hours worth of work.
So we've just hired them to do 500 hours
of work.
They're going to be performing these tasks
and these tasks.
We're going to give them all these tasks
to perform.
And then we're going
to look at the results and
see what we need to do
once the results come in.
But they haven't really delivered a
product to us.
And they might not even have created a
result for us.
We might not have any results during that
500 hours either.
We have just asked them to come in,
do 500 hours worth of work.
That's just a level of effort,
right?
That's it.
Now, whether we actually get something at
the end of it, right, whether we actually
get some kind of deliverable at the end of
it, probably not, right?
We don't know yet, right?
Because it's purely research and
development right now.
So that's the difference then between a
completion contract and a term contract.
Again, just in case you get those terms on
the exam.
So completion contract
then, there's actually a
deliverable that you are
going to get at the end of it.
That's what we normally think of when we
think of a contract.
With a term contract, there's no real
deliverable.
It's just a level of effort.